<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://snlandge.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://snlandge.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-11-20T05:49:48+00:00</updated><id>https://snlandge.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Opportunity to Present My Research in Front of Esteemed Guests</title><link href="https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/presentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opportunity to Present My Research in Front of Esteemed Guests"/><published>2024-10-23T21:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T21:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/presentation/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="a-memorable-event">A Memorable Event</h1> <p>This past week, I had the privilege of presenting my research at an extraordinary event organized by the Economics Department at The Graduate Center, CUNY. The event provided an exceptional platform for sharing groundbreaking ideas, fostering intellectual exchange, and celebrating the achievements of our vibrant academic community.</p> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/Presentation_Paul.jpg" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/Presentation_Paul.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <p>One of the event’s most remarkable highlights was the attendance of <strong>Nobel Laureate Professor Paul Krugman</strong>, a towering figure in the field of economics. It was an incredible honor to present my research on <strong>Intergenerational Occupational Mobility and Income Inequality</strong> to such a distinguished audience. Professor Krugman’s groundbreaking contributions to economics have profoundly influenced my academic journey. Having him in the audience during my presentation was both humbling and inspiring—a moment I will cherish throughout my career.</p> <p>In addition to Professor Krugman’s presence, the event also featured <strong>Ellen Zentner</strong>, the Chief Economic Strategist and Global Head of Thematic and Macro Investing for Morgan Stanley Wealth Management. As a Graduate Center Foundation board member, Ms. Zentner shared invaluable career tips and industry insights with students, bridging the gap between academia and real-world economic applications. Her talk provided a refreshing perspective on the intersection of economics research and industry practices, and it was especially inspiring to hear from someone whose work directly impacts global markets and investment strategies.</p> <hr/> <p>This event has left me more motivated than ever to continue my work on understanding and addressing issues like income inequality and economic mobility. Stay tuned for more updates as I progress on my academic journey!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="The Graduate Center CUNY"/><category term="Economics"/><category term="Research Presentation"/><category term="Paul Krugman"/><category term="Income Inequality"/><category term="Intergenerational Mobility"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A memorable event presenting research at The Graduate Center, CUNY, with Nobel Laureate Paul Krugman in attendance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Experience at the 2024 Inequality by Numbers Workshop</title><link href="https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Experience at the 2024 Inequality by Numbers Workshop"/><published>2024-06-10T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-10T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snlandge.github.io/blog/2024/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<p>I am thrilled to share my experience of attending the 2024 <a href="https://stonecenter.gc.cuny.edu/stone-centers-inequality-by-the-numbers-workshop-returns-in-person-at-the-graduate-center/#"><em>Inequality by Numbers</em></a> Workshop, an event hosted by the Stone Center on Socio-Economic Inequality at the CUNY Graduate Center from June 3-7, 2024. My journey to this workshop started with a wonderful surprise—a notification of my acceptance to the workshop, despite fierce competition from over 125 applicants for just 60 slots. I am deeply honored to have been selected.</p> <p>The acceptance email I received was as follows:</p> <hr/> <p>Dear applicant,</p> <p>We are happy to inform you that you have been admitted to the <a href="https://stonecenter.gc.cuny.edu/stone-centers-inequality-by-the-numbers-workshop-returns-in-person-at-the-graduate-center/#"><em>Inequality by the Numbers</em></a> workshop that will be held at the CUNY Graduate Center, June 3-7, 2024.</p> <p>We received over 125 strong applications for 60 slots. As a result, many applicants have been placed on a waiting list. Therefore, we have two important requests:</p> <ol> <li>Please reply to this email by this Friday, April 12, 2024, to confirm that you accept our invitation to participate in the workshop, or to decline the invitation.</li> <li>If you accept, please send a short bio (approx. 150 words) and a photo.</li> </ol> <p>Please update us as soon as possible if your plans change and you will not attend.</p> <p>We look forward to your participation in June. Further information on the workshop will follow in the near future.</p> <p>Congratulations!</p> <p>Leslie McCall<br/> Associate Director, Stone Center on Socio-Economic Inequality</p> <hr/> <p>Receiving this email was an exciting moment, and I eagerly accepted the invitation.</p> <p>The workshop itself was incredibly well-structured, with each day packed with insightful presentations and discussions. The sessions ranged from topics on labor unions and wealth inequality to health disparities and political participation. Notable speakers such as Leslie McCall, Paul Krugman, and Branko Milanovic shared their invaluable expertise on a wide array of topics. I particularly enjoyed sessions with Branko Milanovic, Suresh Naidu, and Bhash Mazumder, as their insights were closely aligned with my research on income inequality and intergenerational mobility. It was also a privilege to listen to Nobel Laureate Paul Krugman discuss perceptions of the economy, an unforgettable experience.</p> <p>Networking was another invaluable part of the workshop. I had the opportunity to meet and interact with fellow researchers, many of whom are working on similar issues related to income inequality, labor markets, and policy impacts. These connections have already proven fruitful in fostering potential collaborations for future research.</p> <p>Reflecting on my experience, the <a href="https://stonecenter.gc.cuny.edu/stone-centers-inequality-by-the-numbers-workshop-returns-in-person-at-the-graduate-center/#"><em>Inequality by Numbers</em></a> workshop has significantly enriched my understanding of inequality in both theoretical and practical terms. I look forward to applying the knowledge and techniques I gained here to my ongoing research on intergenerational occupational mobility and income inequality.</p> <p>Thank you to the entire organizing team at the Stone Center for creating such a dynamic and engaging workshop. I highly recommend this experience to any scholar working in the field of inequality studies!</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Inequality by Numbers Workshop]]></summary></entry></feed>